Jim Bigelow 3320 Spiceland Drive Boise, ID 83704 January 13, 2013

Balihoo 404 South 8th Street Suite 300 Boise, ID 83702

# Dear Balihoo Human Resources Director:

I am a software developer with a history of delivering successful projects at Hewlett-Packard. I have a longstanding interest in web development and I would bring to your company a broad range of skills, some of which are highlighted below. After reading an article in the Idaho Statesman that mentions a dearth of software developers in the area, I wanted to send you my resume.

I am current in web development topics such as:

- Software as a Service, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, HTML and CSS. Here are the URIs for an example project I am working on:
  - TransForm Idaho Candidate Information
    - Deployed: <a href="http://immense-forest-6797.herokuapp.com/">http://immense-forest-6797.herokuapp.com/</a>
    - Github: <a href="https://github.com/jim-bigelow-swe/candidate\_info.git">https://github.com/jim-bigelow-swe/candidate\_info.git</a>
    - Pivotal Tracker: <a href="https://www.pivotaltracker.com/projects/703687/overview">https://www.pivotaltracker.com/projects/703687/overview</a>
- Behavior and test-driven development, most recently with cucumber and rspec and Agile development practices
- Object Oriented Design using C++ and Ruby, along with experience dealing with non-deterministic, multi-threaded systems.

My main strengths are my ability to master new technologies and my passion for software development. I have both a BS and MS in computer science that I gained while developing software. This combination of experiences gives me the ability to quickly learn new technologies and gain new skills.

I welcome the opportunity to further discuss a position with you. Please contact me at 208-629-0321 or by e-mail at jim.bigelow.swe@gmail.com. I look forward to hearing from you.

Sincerely,

Jim Bigelow

im Bighin

# Jim Bigelow

3320 Spiceland Drive • Boise, Idaho, 83704 • 208-629-0321 (Home), 541-231-3881 (Cell) jim.bigelow.swe@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/JimBigelowSoftwareEngineer

I am a software professional with a history of delivering successful projects at Hewlett-Packard. I have a longstanding interest in web development with recent training in SQL, Software as a Service, Ruby on Rails, machine learning and web analytics. I've developed software on both Unix and Windows and have expertise in fast, efficient XML processing.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

### **Software Development Tools and Environments:**

- Web Development: SQL, Ruby on Rails, Cucumber, Rspec, SimpleCov, XML 1.0, XHTML 1.0, HTML, CSS, XHTML-Print, CSS-Print, Adobe Photoshop
- *Programming Languages*: Ruby, C#, C++, C
- *Unix and Linux*: C, C++, bash and ksh shell scripting, sed, grep, AWK, Yacc, Lex, Make, git, ClearCase, Data Display Debugger (DDD), GDB, gawk, Bison, flex, XEmacs
- Windows: Visual Studio C++ and C#, .NET Framework, CE 6.0, Native C++ interoperability with C#, PowerShell, git, Visual Studio
- Development Methodologies: Agile/Scrum, Behavior and Test Driven Development Configuration management: version control, branching, merging, release management

# **Personal Skills:**

- Excellent written and oral communications
- Excellent interpersonal skills
- Excellent organization and time management skills

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

HEWLETT-PACKARD COMPANY, Boise, ID

# **Software Engineer, Firmware**

2008 - 2012

Technical lead for measuring and evaluating testing efficiency of 30K black box tests for approximately 500K lines of C/C++.

- Designed and implemented software utilities to extract, summarize, compare and visualize code coverage data from test execution, using C#, .NET framework, XML processing classes, and the Visual Studio Code Coverage library.
- Designed and implemented data analysis software utilities for extracting actionable data from the gigabytes of raw coverage data from 400 tests.
- Designed and implemented a mySQL relational database schema for the code coverage data and SQL queries to determine the best test to use when qualifying code changes.

Technical lead for managed/unmanaged interoperation while porting legacy code from Linux to Windows.

- Designed and implemented the managed interface to the legacy code using C#, the .NET framework and Visual Studio 2008 and the Windows development environment for XP and CE.
- Designed and implemented an interoperating layer between legacy C++ code and .NET code allowing reuse C/C++ code with only minor changes, using C++, MSCOM and VS 2008.
- Designed and implemented a C# reentrant, thread-safe initialization interface for the RIP, allowing non-deterministic accesses in the multi-threaded operating environment.
- Designed an efficient XML format for data interchange between managed print pipeline components (C# and .NET), and the native C++ RIP and implemented XML processing in a low overhead thunking layer between the managed data contracts and the legacy RIP data structures. This required designing and implemented efficient XML processing with both C# and the .NET framework and in native C++ using MSXML.

# **Software Engineer**

2005 - 2008

Software architect responsible for delivering a solution where HP LaserJet internal information can be repurposed for multiple uses.

- Created a Model-View-Controller software architecture in C++ for providing device information as an XML document that can be emailed, viewed on a web page or printed. Used Expat, the open-source XML parser, for efficient XML processing in C++ in a Linux development environment.
- Created a lightweight design that was scalable from low- to high-end LaserJet products documented using UML.
- Implemented the design in C++ for a high-end LaserJet and worked with product teams to help them leverage my design and implementation in their products.

Software Engineer 2002 – 2005

Technical lead for LaserJet support for XHTML-Print and CSS Print.

- Represented HP as specification editor and co-author at the Printer Working Group and the World Wide Web Consortium's XHMTL and CSS working groups to complete and gain approval for XHTML-Print and CSS Print Standards.
- Specified the LaserJet implementation of XHTML-Print and CSS print profile.
- Lead a team of software engineers to implement an HP LaserJet Page Description Language in C++ for processing and printing XHTML-Print conforming documents.

#### **EDUCATION**

Master of Science, Computer Science, Algorithms & Data Structures The National Technological University, Fort Collins, Colorado

# **Bachelor of Science, Computer Science,**

Portland State University, Portland, Oregon

# PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

- Web Intelligence and Big Data
- Mastering the .NET Framework with C# 2.0
- Digital Image Processing & Compression
- Software as a Service
- Tracing Documents with Stegatones

# **PUBLICATIONS**

- *XHTML-Print*, W3C Candidate Recommendation, Jim Bigelow, World Wide Web Consortium, January, 2004.
- CSS Print Profile, W3C Candidate Recommendation, Jim Bigelow, World Wide Web Consortium, February, 2004.
- CSS3 Paged Media Module, W3C Candidate Recommendation, Håkon Lie and Jim Bigelow, World Wide Web Consortium, February, 2004.
- XHTML-Print Test Suite, Jim Bigelow, World Wide Web Consortium, April, 2004.
- *Candidate Standard 5102.1-2003 XHTML*TM\_*Print*, Don Wright, Melinda Grant, Jim Bigelow, Peter Zehler, Jun Fujisawa, Printer Working Group, March, 2003.
- Candidate Standard 5102.2-2003 CSS Print Profile, Don Wright and Jim Bigelow, Printer Working Group, March 2003.

### **PATENTS**

- Printing Preparation, US8264710B2, March 2003
- Dynamic Internal Page Registration and Retrieval System, 6489972, December, 2002.